# Sameen Islam

London, England ❖ sameen11@hotmail.com ❖ https://sameen.info/

### PERSONAL STATEMENT

Currently engaged within an MSc in Artificial Intelligence with the goal of being able to apply this technology to novel solutions. Previously graduated with a First Class in BSc Computer Science and have industrial experience within Defence & Space and the Financial Services sector. Being able to tackle a large problem with a team of enthusiastic individuals and reflecting on its impact on the wider world gives me the most fulfilment.

#### Education

University of Southampton

Master of Science, Artificial Intelligence ❖ 2019 – 2021

Relevant Modules: Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Reinforcement Learning, Evolutionary Algorithms, Intelligent Agents

Queen Mary University of London

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science with Industrial Experience ❖ 2014 – 2018 ❖ First Class, Honours

Relevant Modules: Software Engineering, Algorithms & Data Structures, Database Systems, Web Programming.

### **Professional Experience**

Accenture — City of London

System Developer Analyst, 2018 – 2019

Placed in consultancy teams within large financial institutions such as UBS and Clydesdale Bank

- Full-stack developer, working with Java in the backend JavaScript in the frontend
- Agile development, contributed documentation and designed system diagrams for communicating architecture to team located across three continents
- Responsible for maintenance and feature development of forex trade test automation framework which used a message passing interface (MQ) and Spring MVC framework
- Configuration of AWS EC2 cloud instances using Ansible
- Continuous integration using build tools such as Maven, Gradle and TeamCity before deployment
- Selenium and XPath scripting for automatic report generation through web scraping
- Unit testing, version control and application performance profiling using JUnit, Git and Java Flight Recorder
- Bash/Unix scripting for bulk data processing

Airbus — Stevenage, Hertfordshire

Spacecraft Database Developer, 2016 – 2017

Placed in ExoMars Rover development team; European Space Agency's (ESA) first robotic exploration mission on Mars.

- Used Java and internal NoSQL framework to create desktop applications which supported process owner and other database developers
- Built my own Java library on top of internal framework API to support common scripting operations and save time; this library went on to be re-used and developed further by other team members
- Fully documented all work: software spec, test spec, test outcome report and user manual. Presented tool to database community

## **Technology Summary**

- Programming Languages: Python, Java, JavaScript, C#
- Database: Oracle RDBMS, MySQL, SQLite, MS Access, MongoDB NoSQL
- \* Frameworks: pandas, scikit-learn, Robot Operating System, Spark, Hadoop, Django, Unity3D
- Misc: Git, XQuery, Gradle, Maven, Selenium, TeamCity
- Project portfolio: <a href="https://github.com/samisnotinsane">https://github.com/samisnotinsane</a>

### **Interests & Achievements**

- Currently the Social Secretary within Southampton University Salsa Society where I organise socials, integrate new members and organise cross-committee and cross-university events
- ❖ Team won three grand-prizes across London and Amsterdam in various hackathons
- Secured grant of £3,600 from university for team travel to Silicon Valley to pitch winning hack in tech conference
- ❖ Team won £11,500 as grand prize in Sabre Corp's hackathon for Travita, which was covered in the Huffington Post newspaper (http://goo.gl/QDPBVI)